A Finding Aid to the Harold Weston Papers, 1894-1978, bulk 1912-1972, in the Archives of American Art AAA.westharo
Archives of American Art
- Associations and Organizations, 1916-1972; Series 4; (Box 4-10, 37-38; 6.5 linear feet)
  - Adirondack Trail Improvement Society records, 1960s-1969; 4.1; (Box 4; 2 folders)
    Scattered documents include some correspondence with Harold Weston, who served as Chairman of the Adirondack Trail Improvement Society and printed materials. Stationery displays a logo for the society designed by Weston.
    - Correspondence, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Printed Materials, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Committee to Defend America records, 1940-1942; 4.2; (Box 4; 0.4 linear feet)
    Harold Weston served as Chairman of the Keene and Essex County chapters of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (CDA.) The CDA promoted the idea that America should support Britain financially in order to avoid entering the war. Records found in this subseries include correspondence between the National Committee of the CDA, Harold Weston, and others; clippings; financial records; meeting minutes and records; newsletters and bulletins; notes; a petition; printed materials; typescripts of statements and speeches given to promote the CDA, some of which have notes by Weston; suggestions from the National Committee for local chairmen; and miscellany.
    - Correspondence, 1940-1942; (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
    - Clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Essay Contest, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Financial Records, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lists, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Meetings Information, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Notes, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Petition, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Printed Materials, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Statements and Speeches, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Stationery, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Suggestions for Local Chairmen, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors records, 1940-1968; 4.3; (Box 4-5; 0.3 linear feet)
    Harold Weston served as president for the Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors in the 1950s and remained a member into the 1960s. Filed here are audio recordings and other documentation of "An Evening with Louise Nevelson," February 28th, 1967; clippings and other printed materials; scattered correspondence; membership and meetings information; materials relating to the Museum Gift Plan; and documents relating to the history of the association. Also found are Weston's notes taken during a discussion on sculptors by sculptors in 1954. Sculptors present during the discussion include: Caparn, Harkavy, Kekakis, Model, Nevelson, Simkhovitch, Stillman, Vargis, Weschler, and Wingate.
    - "An Evening with Louise Nevelson," File and Audio Recordings, 1967 February 28; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 50-52)
    - Clippings, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Meeting Information, 1954-1971 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Membership Information, 1940-1968 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Museum Gift Plan, 1954-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Notes on Discussion of Sculpture Today by Sculptors,", 1954 February 27 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Organizational History, 1940-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Printed Materials, 1942-1968; (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 4-7)
  - Food for Freedom records, 1943-1949; 4.4; (Box 5; 11 folders)
    Harold Weston organized Food for Freedom in 1943 for providing American aid to refugees in Europe and Asia. He served as Executive Director. Scattered documentation of the organization include clippings and other printed materials; correspondence; financial records from the early 1950s; a copy of a sermon delivered by Reverend A. Powell Davies from All Souls' Church in Washington, D.C. on November 10, 1946 entitled "Lest the Living Forget"; notes; organizational history; materials for a proposed book by Weston concerning Food for Freedom; and records of speeches given by Weston.
    - Articles and Clippings, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Financial Records, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Lest the Living Forget,", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - National Consumers Food Conference Materials, 1943 October 27-28 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Notes, circa 1949 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Organizational History, circa 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Press Releases, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Printed Materials, 1943-1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Proposed Book, 1940s (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Weston's Speech Records, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - International Association of the Plastic Arts/International Art Association records, 1954-1972; 4.5; (Box 5-7, 37; 2 linear feet)
    Weston served as President of the U.S. Committee of the International Association of the Plastic Arts/International Art Association (IAPA)from 1961-1967. Records include a copy of Arts and Artists signed by IAPA delegates; articles and clippings; reports; correspondence; holiday cards from IAPA delegates - many of which are handmade or original works of art; financial documents; membership and meeting information; notes; organizational history; photographs of IAPA delegates and works of art displayed during the 1963 conference held in New York City, and other documents of the conference; and records from the World Academy of Arts and Sciences connected with the IAPA.
    - Art and Artists -- Signed by IAPA Delegates, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Articles and Clippings, 1954-1966; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Concerning Memorials to Weston, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1972; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-29)
    - Holiday Cards, 1960-1970; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
    - "Decisions", 1971 October 29 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Financial Information, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - "IAPA Reel,", 1963; (See also Box 37) (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Interview with Harold Weston, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Membership and Staff Information, 1960-1969; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Meetings Information, 1960-1970; (8 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-10)
    - Materials in French, Concerning Meetings, circa 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Notes, circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Organizational History, 1963-1970; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Photographs, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Press Kit, 1963 October 6-12 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Printed Materials, 1955-1971; (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 17-21)
    - Printed Materials, 1955-1971; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Printed Materials, Not IAPA, 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Questionaire and Responses, circa 1966; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Reports and Proposals, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Schedule for Delegates and Observers, circa 1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - World Academy of Arts and Sciences Materials, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - "IAPA Reel" Recording, 1963; (From Box 5, Folder 34) (Box 37)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government records, 1954-1972; 4.6; (Box 7-10, 37; 2.5 linear feet)
    Harold Weston was a founder of the National Council on the Arts and Government and served as Vice President and President. The group helped to pass legislation forming the National Endowment for the Arts. Found here are annual reports; a ceremonial letter and pen signed by Mayor Robert F. Wagner; clippings; extensive congressional information regarding bills, committees, and testimony; correspondence and memoranda; financial and legal information; grant proposals; lists; membership and meetings information; notes; organizational history; Patron of the Arts Committees information; petitions; a press kit; printed materials; programs information; reports; resolutions; speeches by Weston; and writings.
    - Annual Reports, 1957-1969; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - Annual Reports, Proofs, 1957-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Ceremonial Letter and Pen, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1957-1970; (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 16-22)
    - Congressional Information, 1956-1970; (9 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
    - Congressional Testimony Given by Weston, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1956-1972; (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 11-17)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1956-1972; (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - Financial and Legal Information, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Grant Proposal, circa 1962 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Interviews with Weston Concerning NCAG, 1956-1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Invitation and Guest List, circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Membership Information, 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Meetings Information, 1950-1970; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
    - Notes and Drafts, circa 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
    - Organizational History, 1954-1968; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
    - Patron of the Arts Committees, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Petitions, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Press Kit, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Printed Materials, 1960s; (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 20-23)
    - Printed Materials, Not NCAG, 1958-1965 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Proposed Bill, 1960 May (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Program Plans, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Recordings, 1957, 1965; (See also Box 37) (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Reports, 1960s-1965 (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
    - Resolutions, 1957-1960 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Speeches and Reports by Weston, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Tributes to Members, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Who Pays the Piper," by Weston, circa 1960 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Writings, 1961-1968; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Recordings, from 10th Anniversary Dinner, 1965; (From Box 9, Folder 27) (Box 37)
  - National Endowment for the Arts records, 1961-1972; 4.7; (Box 10; 0.3 linear feet)
    Scattered materials include clippings; congressional documents about bills, committees, and members; correspondence; drafts; financial materials; organizational history; and printed materials from the NEA and other organizations of interest. Information relating to programs funded by the National Endowment for the Arts is filed under Programs Information and contains materials from 1967-1972. Due to it's close affiliation between the National Council on the Arts and Government, some materials from the National Endowment for the Arts may be in the previous series.
    - Clippings, 1968-1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Information, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Drafts and Proposals, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Financial Information, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Notes, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Organizational History, 1967-1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material, Not NEA, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Programs Information, 1967-1972; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - New York State Council for the Arts records, 1960s-1969; 4.8; (Box 10; 2 folders)
    Harold Weston helped to establish the New York State Council for the Arts through his involment in the National Council on the Arts and Government. Materials found include clippings, records from the Committee to Beautify New York City, correspondence, meeting records, organizational history, and printed materials.
    - Clippings, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Committee to Beautify New York City records, 1966-1969; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-17)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Meetings Information, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Organizational History, 1957-1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Printed Material, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Reconstruction Service Committee records, circa 1940s-1942; 4.9; (Box 10; 5 folders)
    Harold Weston served on the Reconstruction Service Committee, established to assist projected rebuilding efforts in Europe. Scattered records include a clipping, correspondence detailing problems the RSC faced in the naming of their group and finding leadership and sponsorship, memoranda, notes, and a proposal for the Civilian Rehabiliation Corps.
    - Clipping, circa 1942 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Memoranda, circa 1942 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Notes, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Proposal for the Civilian Rehabilitation Corps, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, Baghdad records, 1916-1919; 4.10; (Box 10, 38; 0.2 linear feet)
    Weston served with the YMCA, Baghdad in World War I and volunteered with the Baghdad Art Club. Records are from both the YMCA and the Baghdad Art Club and consist of exhibition announcements and catalogs, clippings, correspondence and memoranda between Weston and YMCA volunteers and others, YMCA holiday cards designed by Weston, financial materials, organizational history, a letter of introduction for Harold Weston written in Farsi and a hand-drawn map of rural areas outside Baghdad, YMCA announcements and newsletters, notes, photographs of the Baghdad Art Club exhibition of 1918 and a photo the YMCA Baghdad staff from 1917, YMCA printed materials, and a "University Plan" intended as an educational program for use in Mesopotamia.
    - Baghdad Art Club Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1918 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Clippings, Concerning Exhibitions, circa 1917 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1916-1919; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
    - Holiday Cards, Designed by Weston, 1917-1919 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Financial Information, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Organizational History, Baghdad Art Club, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Letter of Introduction in Farsi and Map of Persia, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Newsletters and Announcements, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Notes, circa 1918 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Photographs, 1917-1918; (See also Box 38) (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Printed Materials, 1917-1919; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 38-40)
    - Rules of the YMCA, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "University Plan,", 1918 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Oversized Photographs, 1917; (From Box 10, Folder 37) (Box 38)
- Commissions and Project Files, 1935-1965; Series 5; (Box 10-12, 38, OV 39; 1.4 linear feet)
  Files that document Weston's Building the United Nations and the Treasury Relief Project sponsored "Procurement Building Murals" are found within the Commissions and Project files series.
  The Commissions and Project Files series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  5.1: Building the United Nations records, 1949-1965
  5.2: Procurement Building Murals records, 1935-1964
  - Building the United Nations, 1949-1965; 5.1; (Box 10-11, 38; 1 linear foot)
    Harold Weston began his painting of the building of the United Nations buildings in New York City in 1949. Found are all materials relating to the painting within the Harold Weston papers including clippings; a list of members belonging to the Committee for the Gift to the United Nations of Harold Weston's Painting Building the United Nations; correspondence, much of which relates to fundraising for the donation of the paintings; financial and fundraising materials; an interview with Weston by Mary Ellen Thomson concerning the paintings; legal documents; photographs including installations, black and white, color and matted photos of the works, and research and reference photos; proposals and estimates for donation; and a proposal for "Voices of Destiny," a U.N. documentary.
    - Clippings, 1950-1957 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Committee for the Gift to the United Nations of Harold Weston's Painting Building the United Nations members, 1954 January (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1965; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 45-47)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1965; (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Financial Information, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Fundraising Materials, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Insurance Policies, 1952-1956 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Weston by Mary Ellen Thomson, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Legal Documents, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, Installations, circa 1955 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, Black and White, circa 1952; (See also Box 38; 4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 10-13)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, Color and Matted, circa 1951; (7 folders) (Box 11, Folder 14-20)
    - Photographs, Research and Reference, circa 1949 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Propsals and Estimates, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Voices of Destiny," Proposal, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Oversized Photos of Works of Art, 1952; (From Box 11, Folder 10) (Box 38)
  - Procurement Building Murals, 1935-1964; 5.2; (Box 11-12, OV 39; 0.4 linear feet)
    Harold Weston's murals for the Procurement Building at 7th St SW and D ST SW in Washington, D.C. were completed under the Treasury Relief Art Project of the federal Works Progress Administration. Found here are clippings, correspondence concerning Weston's affiliation with the Treasury Relief Art Project, a description and other interpretive materials about the murals written and compiled by Weston, exhibtion catalogs and other printed materials, notes about the execution and restoration of the works, photographs and negatives, proposals and plans, preliminary sketches, and Harold Weston's time cards for the art project.
    - Clippings, 1930s-1940s (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1938 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Description of Murals by Weston, circa 1958 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1936-1937 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Map of the United States, circa 1939 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Notes, circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Notes, Restoration, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Notes, Paint and Materials Used, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Photographs of Murals, circa 1940; (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 32-36)
    - Photographs of Murals, Matted, circa 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 37-38)
    - Photographs of Murals, Matted, circa 1936-1938; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Photographs of Murals, Negatives, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Murals, Research, 1930s; (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
    - Press Release, 1938 June 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Proposals and Plans, circa 1936 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sketches, circa 1936; (See also OV 39) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Treasury Department Bulletin, 1935 May-June (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Time Reports, 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Oversized Sketches, circa 1936; (From Box 12, Folder 9) (Box OV 39)
- Freedom in the Wilds records, late 1960s-1976; Series 6; (Box 12-13; 1.8 linear feet)
  Found are all materials relating to Harold Weston's book Freedom in the Wilds (1971), written by Weston as an autobiographical account of his experiences as a painter in the Adirondacks. Records include legal and financial papers, an appeal for financial contributions, correspondence concerning the book, handwritten and typescript drafts including those that are annotated and a precursor to the book entitled "Saga of the Adirondack Mountain Reserve," lists, copy editing notes, photographs and negatives, printed materials, proofs, and published copies of the book.
  - Agreement, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Appeal for Contributions, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Bills and Invoices, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Contributions, circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1973; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 16-19)
  - Correspondence, Thanks, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Faith Weston, 1971-1976 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Drafts, Annotated, circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Drafts, Deleted Chapters, 1971; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
  - Drafts, "Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man,", 1971 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Drafts, General, 1971; (5 folders) (Box 12, Folder 26-30)
  - Drafts, Fragments, circa 1971 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Financial Materials, circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Illustration Printing Information, circa 1971 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Legal Agreements, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Library Lists, circa 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lists, Photographs Needed, circa 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript Draft, circa late 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Notes, Copy Editor, circa 1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Notes, Layout, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Lists, circa 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Order Forms, circa 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Works of Art, circa 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Reproduced in Book, circa 1970; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - Photographs, Negatives, circa 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Printed Material, 1972-1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Printing Information, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Promotional Materials, circa 1971 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Proofs, circa 1971; (4 folders) (Box 13, Folder 18-21)
  - Proofs, "Cut Galley,", 1972 June 21 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Proofs, "Master Proof,", circa 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Proofs, No Corrections, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Proofs, With Illustration, circa 1971 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Reviews, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "Saga of the Adirondack Mountain Reserve" Draft, circa late 1960s; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 27-28)
  - Tax and Royalty Information, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Text Corrections, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Hardback, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Paperback, 1971 October 1 (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Writings and Notes, 1912-1975; Series 7; (Box 13-14; 0.6 linear feet)
  Writings are by Harold Weston, family members, and others. Writings by Weston include a thesis on painting and art from 1915, writings about his travels in the Middle East, articles concerning art and short stories, poems written while in school and to Helen Babbott, academic papers and notes, notes, diary notes, annotated picture postcards from a trip to Europe in 1957, and remarks made my Weston at an annniversary dinner for the Philadelphia Ethical Society.
  Writings by others are by Duncan Phillips, Paul Rosenfeld, Barbara Weston, and Faith Weston. Barbara Weston's "How I Became What I Am" discusses her parents' relationship and her time spent with them. Faith Weston's writings include poetry and notes, and a day diary written while in Europe in 1957. Also found are memorials to Harold Weston, notes labeled "Leaves from a Scrapbook" probably by Weston, general lists, and lists of works of art.
  - By Harold Weston (Box 13)
    - "Landscape Painting and Italian Art,", 1915 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - By Harold Weston (Box 14)
    - "The Campaign in Mesopotamia,", circa 1918 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Six Summer Argonauts--Their Log,", circa 1920s (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Persian Caravan Sketches,", 1921 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Functioning of Color,", circa 1930s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "Paul Looks at Paintings,", circa 1930s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Going Home,", circa 1940 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "A Painter Speaks,", 1938 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Cast They Bread Upon the Waters,", 1953-1955 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Proposed Federal Advisory Commission on the Arts,", 1956 March 12 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Voice of the American Artist,", 1958 March 12 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Nathaniel Dirk,", circa 1960 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      (Probably by Weston)
  - By Others (Box 14)
    - "The Rose Arbour", by Unknown, circa 1914 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "#77--Drama in One Act", by Cecil, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Harold Weston's Adventure", by Paul Rosenfeld, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 14)